Ellen Welsh

Tel: +44 7539789339 Email: ellenwelsh@live.co.uk Location: East London Portfolio: www.ellenwelsh.co.uk // Design Portfolio: www.ellenamelia.com

PERSONAL PROFILE

I achieved a BA Hons Degree in Print Design and Business Studies at the University of Brighton, providing me with a multidisciplinary background in all aspects of design and business. Industry placements during university provided invaluable experience, developing my skills to a professional level. During this time I worked at Rebecca Taylor, New York and Hannah Coffin, London. I was also selected by Eyefix Int. to work as a freelance designer, selling designs to companies including Reiss, Asos and Tommy Hilfiger.

After graduating (2015) I was selected for a graduate position at Karen Millen. This 1 year position was extended for a further year to assist the design team at a higher level. During this time I have designed a number of best selling products and managed a large Atelier print project, developing both my interpersonal and project management skills.

I am currently attending the Blended Developers Professional Programme, whilst maintaining my position at Karen Millen. I am a self-motivated and outgoing individual, with a strong work ethic and I enjoy the challenge of stepping out of my comfort zone. This course has developed my knowledge of software development and in languages such as CSS3, HTML5 and JavaScript. I have excellent initiative and am keen to develop new skills and knowledge.

I am now seeking a position as a junior front-end developer to start an exciting and challenging career within websites and web applications, within a company that provides the opportunity for personal development and career progression.

EDUCATION & IT TRAINING

11/2016- Present Just IT Ltd, London Blended Development Professional Programme

- MTA Software Development Fundamentals (Expected 2017)
- MTA HTML5 Web Application Development Fundamentals (Expected 2017)
- MCSD Programming in HTML5 with JavaScript and CSS3 (Expected 2017)
- MCSD Developing ASP.NET MVC Web Application (Expected 2017)

2011- 2015	University of Brighton BA Honors Print Design & Business Studies; 2:1
2010- 2011	West Suffolk College Art and Design Foundation Diploma
2005- 2010	Thurston Community College A Levels: Textile Design (A*), Media Studies (B), Sociology (C)

2005- 2010 Thurston Community College

9.5 GCSE's at grade C and above: Textile Design (A), English (B), Maths (C)

IT SKILLS

Software Development Skills: C #, Python, Java

Technical Skills: Photoshop, Illustrator, InDesign

Web Technology: Bootstrap, CSS3, HTML5, JavaScript, jQuery (Beginner) GitHub, Angular2

Core Programming Languages: CSS3, HTML5 and JavaScript

PROJECTS:

CMB Equine Dentistry: I developed a multipage website from scratch with HTML5, CSS3 and created the logo using illustrator. This is a live and working website for a growing equine dentistry business. www.cmb-equine-dentistry.co.uk

Whack-A-Mole Game: Working with Java Script, HTML5 and CSS3 to build a 'Whack-A-Mole' game. This accesses local storage, storing the players score and shows text such as 'Score too low' and 'Highscore' to make the game more dynamic for the player.

Weather APP & Route Planner: Working with HTML5, Javascript (jQuery), Restful API, CSS3, AJAX, Bootstrap and JSON I built these web applications to accept user input and provide information relevant to the input.

Earthquake Tracker: Earthquake data from the USGS, by mapping the latitude, longitude and the magnitude of earthquakes in the past 30 days with p5.js. The map imagery is pulled from mapbox.js and the math demonstrated coverts latitude, longitude to x, y via Web Mercator.

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

07/2015- Present Karen Millen, London

Design Assistant- Graduate Scheme

- Working toward design deadlines, preparing for meetings and presentations on a daily basis requires excellent time management and organizational skills.
- I have excellent initiative to work as an individual when working towards a brief, however a collection must be developed as a team. Teamwork and interpersonal skills are invaluable as a designer.
- I have experience in liaising with factories via email and office meetings about products being developed. This includes problem solving as development issues require good communication skills to be resolved.

05/2015- 06/2016 Eyefix Int, London Freelance Print Designer

- I am experienced in being flexible and adaptable as a freelancer working toward diverse briefs on a monthly basis.
- Organization and communication skills are key, and once I have received the brief I used my initiative to create a range of concepts that would appeal to the client.

01/2014- 07/2014 Rebecca Taylor, New York Print Design Intern

This placement required me to use my initiative to organize flights, accommodation and meetings at the US
 Embassy to secure a work visa. I liaised with the HR team to verify start/ end dates and the status of my job.

11/2013- 12/2013 Hannah Coffin, London

Design Studio Assistant

2012- 2014 New Look, Bury St Edmunds

Retail Assistant

2013- 2014 Moreton Hall Health Club, Moreton Hall

Receptionist

2010- 2011 Ickworth House, Suffolk

Waitress

ACHIEVEMENTS AND INTERESTS

COMPUTING:

- Built website for ecommerce sight
- Built design and developer portfolios
- Developing websites and web applications
- Studying with video tutorials, in particular Pluralsight and W3Schools

FUTHER INTERESTS AND ACIEVEMENTS

- Nominated for Business Plan award (2015)
- Prints at New York Fashion Week for Rebecca Taylor, New York F/W 14 and S/S 15
- Offered position as Print and Embellishment Designer at Rebecca Taylor, New York (2014)
- Awarded "Peggy Hyne Award" recognizing achievements on placement year (2014)
- Short listed to Freelance for Kook London and Eyefix Ltd.(2015)
- Selected for Karen Millen graduate scheme (2015)

HOBBIES

- Skiing
- Cinema
- Design & Art Exhibitions
- Design development
- Technology enthusiast

REFERENCES